Luciano Nicacio

6 Sachemus Trail, Brewster MA, 02631

Cell: 508 367 1016 | Email: lucianonicacio@yahoo.com.br

Junior Web Developer brings enthusiasm for an exceptional customer experience and an appreciation for high-quality results to the development, design, and support of company websites. A hard worker and continuous learner who is willing to put in a massive effort to grow his skill set.

Gained valuable and transferrable skills in the food service industry while providing a visually appealing and enticing customer experience. Self-motivated and driven to be a fully contributing team member, be fully prepared for each project, and manage my time well. Brings these same skills to the IT industry.

As an avid reader, gained an understanding of browser compatibility, file-transfer processes, and backups. Interests include both backend and frontend development work.

Training

Freecodecamp Responsive Web Design Certification, 2020 Responsive Website Basics by Coursera, 2020 NUCAMP Bootcamp Web Development Fundamentals, 2020 Udemy and Pluralsight Courses, 2020

Took a deep dive into learning best practices for responsive web design and development. As part of my training, built web sites individually and as part of a team. Examples include:

Luciano Nicacio Portfolio: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap and JavaScript

This is my latest project I created to display all of the other websites I have created.

Mills River Rescue: HTML, CSS (Grid) and JavaScript

This is a project that I am volunteering for. I am building this website for a local non-profit organization. So far I have built the home page, and am currently working on converting it into a WordPress theme as well as creating the remaining pages.

Barber Shop Landing Page: HTML, CSS and JavaScript

Personal project. Built a responsive landing webpage for a barber shop, using HTML, CSS flexbox and the grid layouts. And the JavaScript DOM manipulation to display/hide the toggle menu. Also created a Contact Form in PHP with validation & email sending.

Responsive Travel Industry Website: CSS (Flexbox) and ES6

Personal project. Built a responsive landing webpage, using HTML, CSS flexbox and animation effects. And the JavaScript DOM manipulation.

Color-guessing Game - Team Project

Used JavaScript for functions, variables, arrays, operators, if statements, do ... while loops. Applied knowledge around arrays and generating random numbers, using Math.random() and Math.floor().

Professional Experience

Garde manger - cook: Brewster Fish House, Brewster, Massachusetts, 2019-2020

At this fine dining restaurant, I learned to always look for perfection, even when working under pressure. My goal was to provide the highest quality, so the customer had a nice and memorable experience. As the word spread, it was free advertising for the restaurant.

Luciano Nicacio

Cell: 508 367 1016 | Email: lucianonicacio@yahoo.com.br | Page 2 of 2

Sushi cook: Fisherman's View, Sandwich, Massachusetts, 2018-2019

Teamwork, good communications, and good time management were important at this large-sized restaurant, so that everything worked smoothly behind the scenes and in front of the customer. I spoke directly with the customer to make sure their needs were met. Most importantly, I learned to stay focused and always apply excellent work habits, even under pressure.

Prep cook: Yarmouth House, West Yarmouth, Massachusetts, 2016-2018

At this restaurant I started as a dishwasher and after few months, I was responsible for the whole prep operation. This job taught me to eagerly take responsibility, work independently, and manage my time. Most mornings I worked by myself and had 70% of the things ready, so the cooks could start service.

Cook tournant: Sodexo Catering, Blackrock Dublin, Ireland, 2012-2014

I worked for the world's leading provider of catering, hospitality, and food retail services. I interacted with customers so I could meet their needs. It was a fast-paced environment and required a lot of communication in the kitchen. This is where I learned that communication is everything when you work as a team.

Education

Graduated from University College Dublin, Sport & Exercise Science, 2014